<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.cushycush.wflow</id>

  <name>wflow</name>
  <summary>Shortcuts for Linux — GUI + KDL workflow files</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT OR Apache-2.0</project_license>

  <developer id="io.github.cushycush">
    <name>Matthew Cushing</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
      wflow records, edits, and replays sequences of keystrokes, clicks,
      shell commands, delays, and notifications on Wayland. There's a
      Qt Quick GUI for visual editing and a CLI for cron and scripts;
      both run the same engine.
    </p>
    <p>
      Workflows are plain text in KDL format — diffable in git,
      hand-authorable in your editor, includable into other workflows,
      shareable as a single file. Think macOS Shortcuts, but the
      workflow file is the artifact: no proprietary container, no
      binary blob.
    </p>
    <p>
      Built on wdotool for input injection on Wayland.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.cushycush.wflow.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow</url>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>Qt</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>automation</keyword>
    <keyword>workflow</keyword>
    <keyword>shortcuts</keyword>
    <keyword>wayland</keyword>
    <keyword>macro</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Library page — seven example workflows, each tagged with its action types</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cushycush/wflow/main/assets/screenshots/wflow-library.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <provides>
    <binary>wflow</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.3.3" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          `wait-window` and `focus` now match a window's app_id as well as its title (case-insensitive), so `wait-window "kitty"` succeeds when kitty is running with `nvim` showing as the title.
        </p>
        <p>
          Record Mode no longer silently falls back to a simulated event stream when the compositor's portal can't do RemoteDesktop. The Record page surfaces a clear error instead. Plasma 6 and GNOME 46+ ship the interface; xdg-desktop-portal-hyprland and xdg-desktop-portal-wlr currently don't.
        </p>
        <p>
          Notifications go through the Notification portal directly when running inside Flatpak, narrowing the host-spawn surface to just the user's `shell` and `clipboard` actions.
        </p>
        <p>
          AUR install ships a `.desktop` entry and icon, so wflow shows up in rofi, wofi, Krunner, GNOME Activities, and other XDG launchers.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.2" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          wflow now links wdotool-core in process instead of subprocessing a separate wdotool binary. Input automation works out of the box; no extra package to install.
        </p>
        <p>
          `wflow doctor` reports which input backend it'll use without triggering a portal prompt, and probes the host PATH for notify-send and wl-copy when running inside a Flatpak.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>First public release. Highlights:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>GUI-first leg-2 positioning: a welcome card on first launch, a New-workflow dialog with seven hand-authored example templates baked into the binary, and an inline tutorial overlay anchored to the editor's "+ Add step" footer.</li>
          <li>Security: first-run trust prompt for any workflow file wflow didn't author here. Both the CLI and the GUI surface the prompt with a categorized step summary; a SHA-256 + path entry persists confirmation. See REVIEW.md for the threat model.</li>
          <li>Distribution: Flatpak manifest with host-spawn redirect for shell, key, click, focus, notify, and clipboard actions. AUR (wflow + wflow-git) shipped alongside this release.</li>
          <li>CI / release: GitHub Actions builds + tests on push and produces a draft release tarball on tag.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>Full GUI editor (value/title/option editing, add/delete/reorder, library context menu), real libei Record backend with portal handshake, AUR PKGBUILDs, dual MIT/Apache-2.0 license, full KDL language (vars, flow control, includes, imports, retries, timeouts).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-04-23">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release. CLI runner, KDL workflow format, Qt Quick GUI as a viewer + single-workflow launcher.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
