<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.cushycush.wflow</id>

  <name>wflow</name>
  <summary>Shortcuts for Linux — GUI + KDL workflow files</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT OR Apache-2.0</project_license>

  <developer id="io.github.cushycush">
    <name>Matthew Cushing</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
      wflow records, edits, and replays sequences of keystrokes, clicks,
      shell commands, delays, and notifications on Wayland. There's a
      Qt Quick GUI for visual editing and a CLI for cron and scripts;
      both run the same engine.
    </p>
    <p>
      Workflows are plain text in KDL format — diffable in git,
      hand-authorable in your editor, includable into other workflows,
      shareable as a single file. Think macOS Shortcuts, but the
      workflow file is the artifact: no proprietary container, no
      binary blob.
    </p>
    <p>
      Built on wdotool for input injection on Wayland.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.cushycush.wflow.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow</url>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>Qt</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>automation</keyword>
    <keyword>workflow</keyword>
    <keyword>shortcuts</keyword>
    <keyword>wayland</keyword>
    <keyword>macro</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Library page — seven example workflows, each tagged with its action types</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cushycush/wflow/main/assets/screenshots/wflow-library.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <provides>
    <binary>wflow</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.3.22" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          New `wflow daemon` subcommand. Walks the library, lists every workflow's `trigger { }` blocks, and prints what would be bound. Today this is dry-run only — the v0.4 release will plug in the GlobalShortcuts portal (KDE / GNOME) and Hyprland IPC fallback to actually subscribe and dispatch. This is the diagnostic that lets users author triggers in v0.3.x and see them collected, before the daemon goes live.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.21" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          v0.4 groundwork. Workflows can now declare `trigger { chord "..." }` blocks alongside their steps, parsing and round-tripping through KDL. The runner ignores triggers in v0.3.x — they're inert metadata until the v0.4 daemon ships and starts subscribing to them. Files authored today with triggers stay forward-compatible.
        </p>
        <p>
          Hotstring triggers (`trigger { hotstring "btw" }`) and per-window context (`when window-class="firefox"`) are forward-compatible KDL keys we parse today so future builds don't break old files.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.20" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Stop hotkey is Super+Esc, not plain Esc. Plain Esc stays as a recordable keystroke (workflows that close dialogs / cancel inputs need it); Super+Esc is the chord that asks the recorder to stop without itself being captured.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.19" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Esc stops a recording. The previous "switch to wflow and click Stop" pattern was getting captured into the saved workflow even with the trim heuristic; now the recorder watches the evdev stream for an Esc keypress and triggers stop directly without any focus change. The Esc itself isn't recorded.
        </p>
        <p>
          Library has bulk-delete. Click "Select" in the toolbar to enter selection mode, click cards to add them to the selection, then "Delete N" with one confirmation. Esc cancels selection. The per-card kebab → Delete still works for one-offs.
        </p>
        <p>
          Editor's Delete moved out of the kebab menu into a direct toolbar button.
        </p>
        <p>
          Record buttons are red. The Record tab in the floating nav pill and the central button in the Record page (idle / armed / recording states) all use the err palette so they read as record affordances at a glance instead of generic actions.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.18" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Re-roll of 0.3.17 with the Cargo.lock update that 0.3.17 missed (CI's `cargo build --locked` refused the mismatched lock and the release tarball never built). Same wdotool-core modifier fix as 0.3.17.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.17" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Chord keys (ctrl+l, super+j, alt+tab, …) now actually hold their modifier when replayed on Hyprland and other wlroots compositors. The previous wdotool-core release pressed modifier keycodes via virtual-keyboard but never called the protocol's modifiers() request — wlroots compositors don't auto-derive seat modifier state from virtual-keyboard key events, so the focused client received a bare letter with no Ctrl/Super held. The fix lives in wdotool-core (cushycush/wdotool@fad906a) and wflow pins to that revision until it ships in a published wdotool-core release. Symptom: a recorded `ctrl+l → type "hello world"` workflow that typed `lhello world` (literal `l` followed by the text) into the wrong field on replay.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.16" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Stop-recording tail trim is now semantic instead of time-based. The previous 300ms window missed the natural-paced case (user takes ~800ms to switch back to wflow and click Stop), so saved recordings still ended with a focus-wflow + mouse-move + click sequence the user didn't want. The new rule: truncate at the LAST `WindowFocus { name: "wflow" }` event in the buffer. Workflows can't legitimately switch to wflow's own window mid-record (you can't operate the target app if you're focused on wflow), so that event is always the stop signal.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.15" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Dialogs no longer render the system-styled title/footer bars on top of our custom chrome. The Delete prompt was showing a light header strip with the title text duplicated above the dialog's own header. Suppressed the system header and footer on every wflow Dialog (Delete confirmation, recorder save prompt, New workflow).
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.14" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Stop-click trim now actually persists. The 0.3.10 trim was working on a clone of the events buffer, but the bridge's finalize() read back through the original Mutex and saved the untrimmed list anyway. Trim runs in place on the shared buffer.
        </p>
        <p>
          Recordings auto-insert a 150ms Delay after every focus step. Compositor activate-window requests are best-effort and asynchronous, so the next key/click would land in the previous window if there was no pause. This fixes ctrl+l (and other chords) failing to reach Firefox after a focus step.
        </p>
        <p>
          Editor and library both prompt before deleting a workflow now, with a themed red-confirm dialog ("Delete workflow?") instead of an immediate hard delete. The editor's TopBar gains a triple-dot menu with the Delete entry; the library card menu's existing Delete routes through the same dialog.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.13" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Recorded keystrokes coalesce into a `type` action when they're plain printable characters with no modifiers. A recording where you typed "hello world" used to save as 11 separate `key` steps that fired faster than the target app could process; now it's a single `type "hello world"` step that replays cleanly. Real chords (ctrl+l, Return, function keys) still record as `key` steps.
        </p>
        <p>
          The triple-dot menu on workflow cards and the add-step picker in the editor are themed to match the rest of the app instead of inheriting Qt's system menu chrome.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.12" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Recorder save dialog rewritten to match the rest of the app. The previous version inherited Qt's default Dialog chrome, which on most desktops rendered the TextField text in a color so close to the field background that typing looked invisible. The new dialog uses our dark surface, framed input with the accent border on focus, and our PrimaryButton/SecondaryButton in the footer.
        </p>
        <p>
          Library auto-refreshes when you navigate back to it, so a workflow saved by the recorder shows up immediately. Previously a freshly-saved recording would only appear after restarting the app.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.11" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Editor is no longer a top-level tab in the nav pill. Landing on it without a workflow selected showed an empty page with no useful affordances. Click a workflow in Library to open the editor; press the back arrow in the editor's TopBar to return. Keyboard shortcuts (Ctrl+1, Ctrl+2, etc.) shifted to mirror the new pill order.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.10" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Stop trims the trailing click. The user's switch to wflow and click on the Stop button always landed at the tail of the recording, so every saved workflow ended with a stray focus + click on the wflow window. Trim Click / Move / WindowFocus events that happened in the last 300ms before stop. Trailing keystrokes are kept since users sometimes intentionally end with one (Enter to submit, Escape to close).
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.9" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record now picks up window focus changes and new windows opening on Hyprland by subscribing to its IPC event socket. Both event types record as `WindowFocus` events that turn into `focus` steps when you save the workflow, so a recording can capture "user switched to Firefox, then typed something" instead of just the keystrokes. Sway, KDE, and GNOME equivalents are still TODO.
        </p>
        <p>
          Saving a recorded workflow opens a name prompt with the field pre-selected, so you can pick a real title before the file lands in your library.
        </p>
        <p>
          The recent-events drawer's auto-scroll-to-bottom now uses `positionViewAtIndex(count-1, ListView.End)` deferred via `Qt.callLater`, which actually pins the latest event at the bottom (the previous `positionViewAtEnd()` ran before the new row was laid out and missed the mark).
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.8" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record's recent-events drawer auto-scrolls to the bottom as new events come in, so the latest captured action is always visible. Previously the list scrolled past the bottom of the drawer with no way to follow it without scrolling by hand.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.7" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Two editor fixes. The Record page now drops back to the "ready when you are" idle state when you press Stop instead of leaving the recording animation running and the button stuck on stop. The step list in the editor scrolls when a workflow has more steps than fit in the panel.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.6" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record's evdev fallback now time-throttles mouse motion events. Previously the raw 1000Hz mouse stream saturated the Qt thread queue, the GUI froze, and keyboard events starved on the shared event mutex. Default emit interval is 1000ms (one Move sentinel per second); tune with `WFLOW_REC_MOVE_INTERVAL_MS` for finer or coarser cadence.
        </p>
        <p>
          The chord builder learned the US-en QWERTY letter, digit, and punctuation keys. Recordings used to encode plain letters as `key30` etc., which isn't a valid wdotool keysym and would have failed on replay. Letters now record as `a`, `b`, etc. and chords compose normally (`ctrl+a`, `shift+1`, etc.). Non-US layouts still need editor cleanup; layout-aware mapping is a future polish.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.5" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record Mode now works on Hyprland, Sway, and other wlroots compositors whose portal doesn't ship `org.freedesktop.portal.RemoteDesktop` yet. When the portal handshake fails, wflow falls back to reading `/dev/input/event*` directly via `evdev`, which works on any Linux system as long as the user is in the `input` group.
        </p>
        <p>
          Plasma 6 and GNOME 46+ users still get the portal path with the explicit consent dialog. The fallback only kicks in where the portal interface isn't available.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.4" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Editor fields auto-save as you type. Title, subtitle, and step value edits commit on every keystroke (debounced 600ms), so you don't have to discover that pressing Enter or clicking out is the commit moment. The dirty pill in the toolbar lights up immediately and clears once the save lands.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.3" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          `wait-window` and `focus` now match a window's app_id as well as its title (case-insensitive), so `wait-window "kitty"` succeeds when kitty is running with `nvim` showing as the title.
        </p>
        <p>
          Record Mode no longer silently falls back to a simulated event stream when the compositor's portal can't do RemoteDesktop. The Record page surfaces a clear error instead. Plasma 6 and GNOME 46+ ship the interface; xdg-desktop-portal-hyprland and xdg-desktop-portal-wlr currently don't.
        </p>
        <p>
          Notifications go through the Notification portal directly when running inside Flatpak, narrowing the host-spawn surface to just the user's `shell` and `clipboard` actions.
        </p>
        <p>
          AUR install ships a `.desktop` entry and icon, so wflow shows up in rofi, wofi, Krunner, GNOME Activities, and other XDG launchers.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.2" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          wflow now links wdotool-core in process instead of subprocessing a separate wdotool binary. Input automation works out of the box; no extra package to install.
        </p>
        <p>
          `wflow doctor` reports which input backend it'll use without triggering a portal prompt, and probes the host PATH for notify-send and wl-copy when running inside a Flatpak.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>First public release. Highlights:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>GUI-first leg-2 positioning: a welcome card on first launch, a New-workflow dialog with seven hand-authored example templates baked into the binary, and an inline tutorial overlay anchored to the editor's "+ Add step" footer.</li>
          <li>Security: first-run trust prompt for any workflow file wflow didn't author here. Both the CLI and the GUI surface the prompt with a categorized step summary; a SHA-256 + path entry persists confirmation. See REVIEW.md for the threat model.</li>
          <li>Distribution: Flatpak manifest with host-spawn redirect for shell, key, click, focus, notify, and clipboard actions. AUR (wflow + wflow-git) shipped alongside this release.</li>
          <li>CI / release: GitHub Actions builds + tests on push and produces a draft release tarball on tag.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>Full GUI editor (value/title/option editing, add/delete/reorder, library context menu), real libei Record backend with portal handshake, AUR PKGBUILDs, dual MIT/Apache-2.0 license, full KDL language (vars, flow control, includes, imports, retries, timeouts).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-04-23">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release. CLI runner, KDL workflow format, Qt Quick GUI as a viewer + single-workflow launcher.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
