<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.cushycush.wflow</id>

  <name>wflow</name>
  <summary>Shortcuts for Linux — GUI + KDL workflow files</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT OR Apache-2.0</project_license>

  <developer id="io.github.cushycush">
    <name>Matthew Cushing</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
      wflow records, edits, and replays sequences of keystrokes, clicks,
      shell commands, delays, and notifications on Wayland. There's a
      Qt Quick GUI for visual editing and a CLI for cron and scripts;
      both run the same engine.
    </p>
    <p>
      Workflows are plain text in KDL format — diffable in git,
      hand-authorable in your editor, includable into other workflows,
      shareable as a single file. Think macOS Shortcuts, but the
      workflow file is the artifact: no proprietary container, no
      binary blob.
    </p>
    <p>
      Built on wdotool for input injection on Wayland.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.cushycush.wflow.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/cushycush/wflow</url>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>Qt</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>automation</keyword>
    <keyword>workflow</keyword>
    <keyword>shortcuts</keyword>
    <keyword>wayland</keyword>
    <keyword>macro</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Library page — seven example workflows, each tagged with its action types</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cushycush/wflow/main/assets/screenshots/wflow-library.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <provides>
    <binary>wflow</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.3.10" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Stop trims the trailing click. The user's switch to wflow and click on the Stop button always landed at the tail of the recording, so every saved workflow ended with a stray focus + click on the wflow window. Trim Click / Move / WindowFocus events that happened in the last 300ms before stop. Trailing keystrokes are kept since users sometimes intentionally end with one (Enter to submit, Escape to close).
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.9" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record now picks up window focus changes and new windows opening on Hyprland by subscribing to its IPC event socket. Both event types record as `WindowFocus` events that turn into `focus` steps when you save the workflow, so a recording can capture "user switched to Firefox, then typed something" instead of just the keystrokes. Sway, KDE, and GNOME equivalents are still TODO.
        </p>
        <p>
          Saving a recorded workflow opens a name prompt with the field pre-selected, so you can pick a real title before the file lands in your library.
        </p>
        <p>
          The recent-events drawer's auto-scroll-to-bottom now uses `positionViewAtIndex(count-1, ListView.End)` deferred via `Qt.callLater`, which actually pins the latest event at the bottom (the previous `positionViewAtEnd()` ran before the new row was laid out and missed the mark).
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.8" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record's recent-events drawer auto-scrolls to the bottom as new events come in, so the latest captured action is always visible. Previously the list scrolled past the bottom of the drawer with no way to follow it without scrolling by hand.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.7" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Two editor fixes. The Record page now drops back to the "ready when you are" idle state when you press Stop instead of leaving the recording animation running and the button stuck on stop. The step list in the editor scrolls when a workflow has more steps than fit in the panel.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.6" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record's evdev fallback now time-throttles mouse motion events. Previously the raw 1000Hz mouse stream saturated the Qt thread queue, the GUI froze, and keyboard events starved on the shared event mutex. Default emit interval is 1000ms (one Move sentinel per second); tune with `WFLOW_REC_MOVE_INTERVAL_MS` for finer or coarser cadence.
        </p>
        <p>
          The chord builder learned the US-en QWERTY letter, digit, and punctuation keys. Recordings used to encode plain letters as `key30` etc., which isn't a valid wdotool keysym and would have failed on replay. Letters now record as `a`, `b`, etc. and chords compose normally (`ctrl+a`, `shift+1`, etc.). Non-US layouts still need editor cleanup; layout-aware mapping is a future polish.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.5" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Record Mode now works on Hyprland, Sway, and other wlroots compositors whose portal doesn't ship `org.freedesktop.portal.RemoteDesktop` yet. When the portal handshake fails, wflow falls back to reading `/dev/input/event*` directly via `evdev`, which works on any Linux system as long as the user is in the `input` group.
        </p>
        <p>
          Plasma 6 and GNOME 46+ users still get the portal path with the explicit consent dialog. The fallback only kicks in where the portal interface isn't available.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.4" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          Editor fields auto-save as you type. Title, subtitle, and step value edits commit on every keystroke (debounced 600ms), so you don't have to discover that pressing Enter or clicking out is the commit moment. The dirty pill in the toolbar lights up immediately and clears once the save lands.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.3" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          `wait-window` and `focus` now match a window's app_id as well as its title (case-insensitive), so `wait-window "kitty"` succeeds when kitty is running with `nvim` showing as the title.
        </p>
        <p>
          Record Mode no longer silently falls back to a simulated event stream when the compositor's portal can't do RemoteDesktop. The Record page surfaces a clear error instead. Plasma 6 and GNOME 46+ ship the interface; xdg-desktop-portal-hyprland and xdg-desktop-portal-wlr currently don't.
        </p>
        <p>
          Notifications go through the Notification portal directly when running inside Flatpak, narrowing the host-spawn surface to just the user's `shell` and `clipboard` actions.
        </p>
        <p>
          AUR install ships a `.desktop` entry and icon, so wflow shows up in rofi, wofi, Krunner, GNOME Activities, and other XDG launchers.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.2" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>
          wflow now links wdotool-core in process instead of subprocessing a separate wdotool binary. Input automation works out of the box; no extra package to install.
        </p>
        <p>
          `wflow doctor` reports which input backend it'll use without triggering a portal prompt, and probes the host PATH for notify-send and wl-copy when running inside a Flatpak.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>First public release. Highlights:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>GUI-first leg-2 positioning: a welcome card on first launch, a New-workflow dialog with seven hand-authored example templates baked into the binary, and an inline tutorial overlay anchored to the editor's "+ Add step" footer.</li>
          <li>Security: first-run trust prompt for any workflow file wflow didn't author here. Both the CLI and the GUI surface the prompt with a categorized step summary; a SHA-256 + path entry persists confirmation. See REVIEW.md for the threat model.</li>
          <li>Distribution: Flatpak manifest with host-spawn redirect for shell, key, click, focus, notify, and clipboard actions. AUR (wflow + wflow-git) shipped alongside this release.</li>
          <li>CI / release: GitHub Actions builds + tests on push and produces a draft release tarball on tag.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-04-25">
      <description>
        <p>Full GUI editor (value/title/option editing, add/delete/reorder, library context menu), real libei Record backend with portal handshake, AUR PKGBUILDs, dual MIT/Apache-2.0 license, full KDL language (vars, flow control, includes, imports, retries, timeouts).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-04-23">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release. CLI runner, KDL workflow format, Qt Quick GUI as a viewer + single-workflow launcher.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
